Jacob Higdon



hjake123@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/jacob-higdon-0x00



5129196507



https://github.com/hjake123

Summary

Passionate CS graduate skilled in using C++, Java, Python, C# and JavaScript to architect and develop general software, especially using Object-Oriented principles.

Completed U.H. Computer Science B.S. and the U.H. Data and Society Minor, both of which provided software development opportunities. Self-directed a research project as part of the Pharis Fellowship in the summer of 2021 (see Experiences).

Experience



Researcher

U.H. Pharis Fellowship

Jun 2021 - Aug 2021 (3 months)

Led a research project examining inequality in the criminal justice system with respect to people who identify in gender and sexual minorities. This project was performed in a Jupyter notebook (so, in Python) and used the pandas library for all data management and statistics. The project was entirely self-led, with supervision by the professors only serving as a source of advice. The project was continued in the following semester, after which point it was presented at the University of Houston Undergraduate Research Day.

Modded Minecraft Developer

N/A

Jan 2022 - Feb 2023 (1 year 2 months)

(This section describes a relevant hobby project.)

Designed, constructed, and released three Java-based modifications ("mods") for the video game Minecraft. These mods used the Forge modloader and API, as well as mixin, to add and adjust various features of the game. This process requires navigating a code-base with obfuscated parameter and poor documentation, and demands an understanding of Functional Interfaces, Client-Server Networking, JSON, and of course debugging using an IDE. These projects have, to date, amassed 4,852 downloads.

Here is a link to the github repo of one such mod, for context: https://github.com/hjake123/reactive



JavaScript Developer for Software Development Class Group Project

N/A

Feb 2022 - Apr 2022 (3 months)

Built a JavaScript + NodeJS Web App powered by PostgreSQL for a hypothetical fuel quoting service, in collaboration with 2 other developers. Created the middleware and worked on the HTML frontend for the profile management and quote generation pages, which interfaced with a frequently-changing backend made by another developer. This project utilized some aspects of Test-Driven Development, using jest as our testing platform.

Github repository, for the curious: https://github.com/4353-slot-12/assignment-4

Database Systems Class Group Project Team Lead

N/A

Mar 2022 - Apr 2022 (2 months)

Led a group including 4 other developers to create an SQL-powered .NET application for a hypothetical art museum. Managed the deployment of the app on Azure Web Services, built two of the project's pages, implemented a login system, and worked to resolve issues in others' portions of the project where necessary.

Link to the github repository, for the curious: https://github.com/hjake123/dt-team2

Education



University of Houston

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science

Aug 2019 - Dec 2022

Over the course of 7 semesters I graduated with a Bachelor's of Science in Computer Science and a Minor in "Data and Society" (from the Honors College catalogue of minors).

Skills

HTML • R (Programming Language) • JavaScript • Leadership • Java • Python (Programming Language) • C++ • C (Programming Language) • Communication • Git

Honors & Awards



Eagle Scout - National Eagle Scout Association (DC)

Earned the Eagle Scout rank in BSA



University Honors - Honors College

Dec 2022

Graduated while completing all the requirements set out by the UH Honors College. See details here: www.uh.edu/honors/students/current-students/graduation/requirements-for-honors-graduation/